This helped me understand the app so
much better and saved me so much time of
having to like investigate all of these
RPC IDs. Uh, it took about 15 minutes to
set up and that investment paid massive
dividends and I got a 20k bounty because
of this.
>> Best part of when you can just, you
know, critical think, right?
Yeah, dude.
[Music]
>> All righty, hackers. We got the This
Week in Bug Bounty segment. Three
entries this time. First one up is from
a collaboration between Hack the Box and
Hacker 1. Uh there's a AI red teaming
CTF going on from uh September 9th to
September 19th and it gives you an
opportunity to try 10 different
challenges. Uh what do they say here?
Over nine escalating challenges and one
final boss. You'll work through AI
powered apps where the goal is to
override filters, bypass logic, and
extract data you shouldn't have access
to. So if you are trying to kind of cut
your teeth a little bit into AI red
teaming, this is a cool opportunity to
work with Hack the Box and Hacker 1. So
check it out if you're interested. link
will be in the description. Um, next up
is Yes We Hack, one of the one of the
amazing u sponsors that we have of the
podcast. Just wanted to let us uh have
us let you know that they are going to
be at RootCon this year in uh the
Philippines. They've got a team out
there um from September 25th to 26th.
Definitely go say hi, interact with
them. Uh if you see them around, uh
they'd love to to meet you and and hang
out. Um, and then also in line with Yes,
We Hack, uh, they recently released
their hardware monitor dojo challenge of
the month. Um, this time we got an LFI
and it's looking pretty juicy, you guys.
Um, so definitely go check that out if
you're wanting to refine some of those
Ruby LFI related skills. All right,
that's all we got for this weekend bug
bounty segment. Let's head back to the
show.
All right, hackers, here's the deal. Uh,
this week we've had a bunch of
cancellations and sickness and stuff
like that. So, um, this episode's going
to be a little bit on the fly. And
essentially, it is I was thinking to
myself, what am I excited about? What do
I want to go yap about for 15 minutes to
give them an episode to listen to this
week? And, um, what I'm excited about is
Kaido. And so, what I'm going to cover
today is a couple new uh, features and
plugins that have been released in Kaido
um, over the past couple months that I
think you should know about uh, and that
I use on a regular basis. All right, so
um, let's jump right into it. Whether
you use Kaido or Burp, I think these are
really um important features to be aware
of because they push the community
forward in general, right? So even if
you um even if you're not using Kaido,
maybe you should think about these
features and how you can do them in Burp
uh or or you know sort of bring par to
the ecosystem there um so that we can
all enjoy better HTP proxies. All right,
so let's jump right into it. first one
um sort of and also I will add this is
sort of extracted from the presentation
that I gave at Defcon in in part. I'm
definitely not going to be able to go
into as much detail as I did there but
um this is a little bit of the content
of what I talked about at Defcon.
So if you were there sorry for the for
the repeat but um for the most of you
this will be newish content. Okay. Um,
for those of you familiar with Kaido,
there's this concept of HTTPQL. And
HTPQL is something we use inside of
Kaido to query different um sets of data
uh through throughout the the Kaido
ecosystem. You know, sometimes we use it
for search, sometimes we use it for
filtering, um conditional things like
match and uh match and replace or um
conditional intercept, that sort of
thing. Um, and one of the things I found
myself doing pretty often was like, "Oh,
I saw a request, you know, five minutes
ago and I need that request and I I
scrolling and I can't find it. So, I'm
just going to search for it really
quick." Um, and one of the things that
Kaido does allow you to do is search for
the time that a request was created in.
Um, so I was, you know, sort of trying
to get some workflows in place to to um
figure out how to search quickly within
Kaido um in within a certain time frame.
And I built into this uh plugin called
Even Better this uh feature called
common filters. And it essentially what
it does is it gives you a list of
filters. I'm going to go ahead and pull
it up here because I can't remember
which ones um I have. but it's recent
which is within the last 5 minutes, 1
hour, 6 hours, 12 hours, 24 hours. And
so you can just kind of attach
timestamps really quickly to your HPQL
queries and it will limit the amount of
um you know results that you get uh
which makes the search instantaneous um
and also allows you to sort of narrow in
on the exact time frame that you want.
Uh so that's called common filters. They
automatically update every minute uh so
that you can get the latest um you know
updated version of that filter and
they're very convenient to use. So check
that out if you're using um HTPQL and
Kaido. Also another feature that I
recently integrated into the even better
plugin is uh convert workflow command
pallet entries. So a a lot of people
don't know this but um Kaido has a
command pallet that is uh pretty awesome
in my opinion. Um, and you can activate
it by pressing control K. And what it
what the uh integration with convert
workflows will do is it will allow you
to run um Hold on, my dog is barking.
All right, dog has been dealt with. I'm
back. Um, anyway, command pallet uh
entries have the various convert
workflows that you define within Kaido,
which is super great. So you just type C
and then the name of the convert
workflow that you want to do and it
takes your currently selected text
inside of Kaido and uh runs the convert
workflow on that. Uh so if you're
actively in replay, you know, where
you're modifying stuff, it makes it
super easy to be like, okay, you know,
you're on code this basic code this
super quickly um with command pallet
without having to take your hands off
the keyboard. um if you're not inside of
Replay or like an editable editor, it
just copies it right to your clipboard,
which is super nice for getting stuff
into the right format um so that you can
use it later in inside your clipboard.
Um so I've been using this really often.
This is like probably the feature that
I've integrated into my workflow uh the
the quickest with Kaido, you know, when
a new feature comes out because it just
makes sense to have these right at the
tip of your fingers. And it using the
command pallet is just really nice
because it's consistent with the way
that I think about, oh, I need to basic
code. So, you know, control K basics for
encode. Boom, done. Um, so definitely
check those two features out. Those are
in the even better plugin um in the
Kaido store. Okay, next thing I'm
excited about, which I've talked about a
couple times already, so you know, just
bear with me, guys, is the Notes++
plugin is amazing and it really has
changed the way that I make notes in
Kaido. Okay. Um, and it there there's a
couple reasons for that, but the feature
that I use the most is the um Windows
shift N feature in Notes++, which you
can be in Replay, you're you're doing
your thing, you find a gadget, you find
something you need to take a note on,
and you just press Windows shift N, and
it pops up in a little box that's
attached to your current open note in
Notes++.
Um, and you can, uh, write whatever you
want in there. And uh it there's a
little box that's automatically checked
that says attach current context. And
what it will do is insert your note into
the the the note that you have in your
in your plugins uh notes plus+ tab, but
it will also attach the current replay
tab like a a beautiful graphical rep
representation of the of the um current
note. So, let me go ahead and and for
those of you that are on um for the
those of you that are on YouTube, I'm
going to go ahead and share my screen
really quickly here so you can see what
I'm talking about because it it is it is
quite nice. Um here we are.
Here it is right here. So, you can see,
you know, the the beautiful graphical
representation of this specific request.
And then you can click on it and jump
right over into this um you know, a HTTP
request in replay. Um super clean. uh
very useful for making sure that you
know where all of your requests are. Um
and I use it constantly really. I kind
of struggled with taking notes before,
but this makes it so easy that I I
actually do it now. Um one of the
improvements that I would like to kind
of see in this area, which is something
we're thinking about implementing, is
the ability to do voice notes. And I
know Mon did a uh a plugin a while back
um sort of that had a feature like this,
but it would be really awesome if we
could just press a key binding and then
just say blahy blahy blah blah blah, you
know, enter and and that would be
automatically converted into into text
and stored in the note for us. I think
that would be the maximum uh amount of
friction reduction. Like that that would
just make it super easy. Um but I guess
you do have to have like your microphone
and stuff like that. Um, I don't I don't
normally hack like this with my
microphone right next to my face and
stuff like that. So, um, yeah, I guess I
guess there's some workshopping to do
there, but I think it would still be
really helpful.
Um, I yeah, I think that's good for
Notes++. Um, definitely check it out if
you're if you're, you know, taking notes
inside of your uh, kind of environment.
Um, next up is shift agents. And I've
talked about shift agents, I believe
once or twice before in the podcast, uh,
but I have recently started using them
and it's super helpful. Okay. Um, so
what I've done is I've created
a couple micro agents and the one that
actually has found me a vulnerability or
I guess this one's more of a gadget that
I've chained into a vulnerability uh is
my domain restriction bypass uh uh
microaggent. Okay, so uh for those of
you that haven't heard of shift agents,
let me explain what it is. Essentially,
shift agents is the ability for you to
um define little micro agents within
Kaido. Okay? And so you can give it
like, you know, system prompt or
whatever. It's got all the tools to like
modify your current replay tab and that
sort of thing. Um, and then you you give
it task and it, you know, creates a
to-do list, goes through the to-do list,
if it finds something interesting, it
creates a finding for you to alert you
of what it found. Okay. So, it allows
you to sort of build your own hackbot
workflows within Kaido. Um, and the one
that I built, like I said, was a domain
restriction bypass uh um uh microaggent.
And I I had a scenario where I was
looking at an open redirect um looking
for an open redirect and I handed it off
to this agent and it was able to go
through my whole workflow uh
successfully you know that I would have
done manually. Okay, let's check the
dots for reax. Let's you know check an
ends with let's check an invalid you
know um parsing of um you know the URL.
Let's check unic code normalization. and
it was actually able to find a
vulnerability um via the you know at
sign at the front of the URL. Um and and
that was something that I had documented
in the various you know uh uh system
prompt sections that I passed into it
and then it was able to correctly
identify that and create a finding with
the open redirect. Um,
so that saves me time and effort, right?
First I I give it a stab at it, right?
So for those of you that haven't played
around with it, essentially how it works
is you open up a replay tab, you pop
open the little um agent side window,
you give it uh the system prompt you
want and then you know some just in time
um instructions and then you essentially
delegate that replay tab to the AI.
Then, you know, you continue doing your
thing. You come back, you know, either
it creates a finding and you see it on
the side, or you come back and you can
review what it did by sort of tabbing
back and forth between your replay
session, um, and seeing what exactly it
did. Uh, so for me, that's been working
quite well. I've been pleased. I was
pleased that it was able to implement
that. It saved me time. I think I've
used less than $7 total right now um as
far as um money goes, you know, to to to
fund the AI um on Open Router. Um yeah,
and and I've had decent success with
Gemini. Uh that's the one I've been
using currently, but I've heard from,
you know, the Xbox writeups and stuff
like that that uh GPT5 is like a big
level up as far as hacking performance
goes. So, I'm excited to play around
with that a little bit as well. So, um I
think now is the time, you know, I guess
without without, you know, futing it too
much. This industry is going to change
for sure within the next year. Um and
has changed already. You know, if you're
not using AI at all in your workflow,
you know, if you're not like at least
having a Gemini tab open and being like,
hey, you know, tell me about this, tell
me about that. Um or using it to parse
docs or, you know, attack vector ID or
do do source code review. Um then you're
behind to be perfectly frank with you.
Um, but I think it's going to continue
to progress in such a way that if you
are not integrating AI directly into
your workflow to save you time, then
you're going to get even further behind.
So, I think now is a good time to start
developing these microaggents. You don't
have to use them constantly, but just
realize that um developing these
microaggents is not a a sunk cost
because eventually uh it they're going
to work. Eventually, they're going to
work amazing, right? Um, and as as you
start refining your prompt over time,
that prompt, you know, can be ported.
Okay, maybe shift agents isn't the thing
you use, maybe you use something else,
right? But those prompts can be ported
into, you know, other AI um assisted
hacking um systems. Okay, so go ahead
and get started writing some some some
system prompts. And I think Shift AI is
a great great place to do it. Okay, um
you can grab that in the Kaido store. By
the time this episode is out, the new
version of Shift Agent should be
integrated into Shift in the Kaido
plug-in store. So, go grab it, play
around with it, write yourself a system
prompt. Um, these episodes are typically
longer, right? They're not these little
little short episodes. So, the time that
you would have spent listening to CTB
today, okay, go ahead and and take that
and build yourself at least one system
prompt um in in Shift Agents and uh
throw it at something this week. Okay, I
think that'll be a good a good step for
most of you to start integrating AI into
your actual hacking workflow.
All right, next up is uh Drop, which is
uh just super awesome. Okay, this is a
plugin that I wrote in architected and
actually this is probably my crown jewel
as far as engineering goes uh because
it's a pretty sick plugin and it uh is
endto-end encrypted and it allows you to
send uh uh like various objects in Kaido
match and replace rules re you know
replay tabs uh HTTP requests from HP
history scopes filters whatever send it
to your friend instantly within Kaido.
So, all you do is you grab your
friend's, you know, uh, PGP public key,
you drop it into into drop. Drop it into
drop. See what I did there? Um, you drop
it into drop, and then now you just
literally on any object in in Kaido, top
right corner, typically there's like a
little drop button. You click that,
click their name, and then boom, it's in
their Kaido instance. Super seamless,
extremely easy to set up. Publicly
hosted instance with uh full endto-end
encryption using PGP. You can read the
spec, and all the code is public. so you
can see exactly what we're running. Um,
definitely use it if you collaborate at
all with people. It is extremely useful.
Um, all right, that's as far as it goes
for plugins. Let me tell you guys about
a couple more things and then we'll call
it a wrap for today. Um, lately I have
been having a lot of fun with workflows
in Kaido. um workflows are the way for
you to do sort of quick and dirty
automation um within Kaido and they're
gaining a lot of capability and they're
going to continue to gain a lot of
capability um over the next quarter or
two. Um one of the things that I've been
doing recently is using uh the auto
session refresher functionality that I
built in in uh in in the workflow. And
if you guys are interested in figuring
out how to do this um you can go to
kaido.riterator.com rinerator.com and
I've got a lab there that I set up for
the becoming a Kaido power user workshop
at DevCon.
Um, and there's a little lab where you
can download the workflow and that sort
of thing. But the TLDDR of the situation
is you can create a passive workflow in
Kaido that automatically looks at for,
you know, a specific host, grabs a
specific set of cookies or cookies or
whatever, and then creates an
environment variable, which is like sort
of a way to store data within Kaido, um,
with those actual values. And then uh
and it just does that constantly.
Anytime a request comes through HTP
history then whenever you are looking to
like send a request in replay and you
press send and it's like oh 43 your
session expired. You're like [__] now I
got to go create another replay tab and
then no everything gets so messy. So the
the right way to do it is have the
session refresher automatically extract
the session and then you just create a
replay placeholder with that specific
environment variable that's always
updated and then you never have to worry
about updating your session ever again
and your session will always be live. So
um very very useful piece of
functionality there. Um the template
workflow for that is at
kaido.inerator.com under the session uh
monitoring lab. So go ahead and check
that out um if you want to get your
hands on it. Also, the latest version of
Kaido comes with finally I convinced
them to ship it uh my top level
navigation highlighter plugin. Now, this
is literally one of the most
transformational things that I've ever
seen in in in HP um proxies. Okay. Um
and essentially what it does is it just
uses sec fetch headers to highlight top
level navigations in Kaido. And that is
finally shipped native with Kaido, which
is great. So just go to passive
workflow, turn it on, and then when you,
you know, do a top level navigation in
your browser or an iframe level
navigation, you'll see that highlighted
inside of HTP history, which makes it
super easy to orient yourself within
Kaido. If you are not using this, your
life will change when you use this,
okay? So please just give it a shot. I'm
begging you because it is super helpful
for orienting yourself in HTP history.
And I have literally no idea how I lived
without it. like
it takes forever to find any request now
without this. I I I loaded up a raw
version of Kaido the other day and I was
like uh how does anybody do this in Burp
or in raw Kaido without this on? Um so
definitely life-changing. All right,
last but not least, I wanted to share a
little case study of how I used Kaido
workflows recently um to really really
enhance my hacking experience. Okay,
there's a target that I was hacking on
that instead of sending requests to a
specific path, they would just send it
to all to the same path and include an
RPC ID. Okay, that RPC ID was just a
six-digit alpha numeric string. And it
was super annoying because you could
never tell what was happening in the
app. Um, however, in the JS files, there
was sort of a mapping. It wasn't a
direct mapping. was like, you know,
couple hundred characters separated, but
they were always, you know, the same
couple hundred characters separated
between the RPC ID and the actual like
name, human friendly name of whatever
that RPC correlated to. Um, so I was
able to create a workflow plus match and
replace rule system here that allowed me
to sub in that ID um the the human
readable value for that directly into
the HTP request um at at send time which
allowed me to understand this app so
much better without having to constantly
crosscorrelate these RPC ids. Okay, so
here's how I did it. I created a passive
workflow and what that passive workflows
run automatically anytime a request
comes through HTTP history. That passive
workflow would look for a specific um uh
you know reax in the in JavaScript files
and it would extract the RPC ID to human
readable path correlation. Okay. And it
would store that in a Kaido environment
variable. So now you've got a map of RPC
ID to path. Boom. Uh extracted with
passive workflows. Then I created a
match and replace rule in Kaido which um
adds a query parameter uh which first
you know checks the reax to make sure
that this request is you know the one of
the requests that has the RPC ID and
then it adds a query parameter to the
request. Um so and then sorry let me let
me be clear the replacer for the match
and replace was a workflow right? So
this is one of those sort of advanced
workflows that you can do um or advanced
match and replace rules that you can do
with Kaido where you match on a reax and
then you your replacer is actually
generated by a convert workflow. Okay.
So um you match on the reax, you extract
the RPC ID from that reax and inside of
the convert workflow you crossorrelate
that um RPC ID with your all of your
environment variables, right? and you
say, "Okay, oh, I found the RPC ID. Now
I've got the corresponding path. Now,
let me go ahead and add a um query
parameter to that specific request that
says human readable path equals and then
you know whatever you crossorrelated it
to. And then uh I was able to look at
the modified request in search um and
just kind of use that as my HTP history
for now. um where I could see the flow
of the actual human readable versions of
the HTTP requests um as they were coming
through. This helped me understand the
app so much better and saved me so much
time of having to like investigate all
of these RPC IDs. Uh it took about 15
minutes to set up and that investment
paid massive dividends and I got a 20k
bounty because of this. And the 20k
bounty was literally like an idor in the
front of this app, but nobody found it
because everything was so obuscated and
uh and hard to to work on. So take some
time, invest deeply in these um uh in
these sort of ways to improve your your
automation uh and you'll find some
really crazy stuff. All right, guys.
That's a wrap for today. I got to call
it. Um yeah, I know this isn't the
typical episode, but I hope you guys
enjoyed it and got something out of it
anyway. Um, all right. We'll see you
next week. Peace. And that's a wrap on
this episode of Critical Thinking.
Thanks so much for watching to the end,
y'all. If you want more critical
thinking content, uh, or if you want to
support the show, head over to
ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.